<page>
    <h1>Using Filters</h1>
    <text>
        So far we’ve seen <docs-ref link="/PyTgCalls/Decorators">how to register a decorator</docs-ref> function that executes every time an update comes from the server,
        but there’s much more than that to come.

        Here we’ll discuss <docs-ref link="/PyTgCalls/Filters">filters</docs-ref>. Filters enable a fine-grain control over what kind of updates are allowed or
        not to be passed in your callback functions, based on their inner details.
    </text>
    <separator/>
    <h2>Single Filters</h2>
    <text>Let’s start right away with a simple example:</text>
    <list>
        <item>
            <text>
                This example will show you how to only handle updates that are an Incoming Call
                and ignore any other update. Filters are passed as the first argument of the decorator:
                <syntax-highlight>
                    from pytgcalls import filters
                    ...
                    @pytgcalls.on_update(filters.chat_update(ChatUpdate.Status.INCOMING_CALL))
                    def on_incoming_call(client, update):
                        print("Incoming call!", update)
                </syntax-highlight>
            </text>
        </item>
    </list>
    <h2>Combining Filters</h2>
    <text>
        Filters can be used in a more advanced way by inverting and combining more filters together using bitwise operators <code>~</code>, <code>&amp;</code> and <code>|</code>:
        <list>
            <item>
                <item>Use <code>~</code> to invert a filter (behaves like the <code>not</code> operator).</item>
            </item>
            <item>
                <item>Use <code>&amp;</code> and <code>|</code> to combine filters together (behaves like the <code>and</code> and <code>or</code> operators).</item>
            </item>
        </list>
        Here are some examples:
        <list>
            <item>
                <text>
                    This example will show you how to only handle updates that are <b>left</b> updates from a specific <b>chat</b> and ignore any other update:
                    <syntax-highlight>
                        from pytgcalls import filters
                        ...
                        @pytgcalls.on_update(~filters.chat_update(ChatUpdate.Status.LEFT_GROUP) &amp; filters.chat(1234567890))
                        def on_incoming_voice_call(client, update):
                            print("Left chat!", update)
                    </syntax-highlight>
                </text>
            </item>
            <item>
                <text>
                    This example will show you how to only handle updates that are <b>left</b> updates or <b>incoming call</b> updates and from a specific <b>chat</b>:
                    <syntax-highlight>
                        from pytgcalls import filters
                        ...
                        @pytgcalls.on_update(filters.chat(1234567890) &amp; (filters.chat_update(ChatUpdate.Status.LEFT_GROUP) | filters.chat_update(ChatUpdate.Status.INCOMING_CALL)))
                        def on_incoming_voice_call(client, update):
                            print("Incoming voice call or left chat!", update)
                    </syntax-highlight>
                </text>
            </item>
        </list>
    </text>
</page>